4105916249 ryan.hadfield@gmail.com Salt Lake City, Utah

CONTACT INFORMATION

Website: www.ryanhadfield.com

GitHub: https://github.com/ryanhadfield

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with 10+ years in marketing, project management, sales, and product development. Graduate of the University of Utah Coding Boot Camp with skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and MERN stack. Extensive eCommerce platform management and sales experience ranging from strategic marketing & execution to key account management, including an understanding of EDI fulfillment and freight logistics. Seasoned buyer/product developer with experience in all processes involved from conception, design, and initial sourcing, to product launch, including FOB buying. A well-established passion for products, the outdoors, and a good eye for a trend.

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+
- Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap
- eCommerce Platform Management
- GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL
- Product Design & Development
- Brand Management

EXPERIENCE

Pro Purchase Program Manager, Liberty Mountain, May 2013 - May 2020, Salt Lake City, UT

- Managed the Influencer/Pro sales channel and eCommerce platform for an outdoor gear manufacturer and distributor representing over 900 brands and 30,000+ products in the outdoor seament.
- Generated double-digit sales growth YOY for 6 years and established a \$2M sales channel.
- Increased sales through targeted marketing, new customer acquisition, and increased brand offerings.
- Collaborated with marketing to develop targeted email campaigns, competitive e-commerce website features, and social media content.
- Introduced and implemented 3rd party pro purchase partnerships to increase overall sales and grow the influential customer base.
- Played an integral role in the deployment of new D2C eCommerce sites for the organization.
- Exhibited at industry trade shows as well as marketing events targeted toward B2B and D2C customers.

Procurement Coordinator, Black Diamond Equipment, Apr 2011 - Sep 2012, Salt Lake City, UT

- Managed the implementation and use of project management solutions to increase organization and efficiency of the supply chain department.
- Performed as a procurement manager and finished goods buyer for several product categories.
- Promoted and maintained relationships with vendor partners for new and carry over products and categories.
- Managed and instructed product reworks to turn affected products back into sellable inventory

and complete the commercialization stage.

- Owned the product development cycle from SMS to the finalized commercialization stage.
- Coordinated the tracking of commodities, labor, and exchange rates for the seasonal carry-over cost negotiation processes.
- Reported to senior-level management on the company's global inventory positions and collaborated with sales to strategically manage sell-through.

International Development & Production Manager, Diamond Select Toys & Collectibles, LLC, Apr 2005 - Apr 2011, Timonium, MD

- Managed international product development, promotion, and manufacturing bringing over 200+ products to market.
- Acted as liaison with international factories, vendors, and representative groups.
- Worked closely with the company's Hong Kong consultants to establish deadlines, manage costs, and ensure product quality.
- Promoted and sourced new factories/vendors, developing new techniques and innovations for products.
- Built and maintained BOMs and tech packs for each project with our international vendors.
- Reviewed and tested samples from prototype to FEP stage of the product development cycle.
- Communicated scheduling, cost, or any other information which would benefit management.

Sales Specialist, Recreational Equipment Inc, Apr 2000 - Apr 2011, Timonium, MD

- Maintained a working knowledge of REI products and services and used this knowledge to sell products and services that specifically met the needs of B2C customers.
- Administered clinics on Mountaineering, Backpacking, Camping, Snowshoeing and Climbing to customers, fellow employees, and community groups.
- Built customer loyalty through the company's membership program, outlining the features and benefits to customers to promote enrollment.

Key Account Sales Manager, Diamond Comic Distributors, Inc, Nov 2001 - Nov 2005, Timonium, MD

- Managed detailed order processing and sales operations for 20+ national and international key accounts.
- Introduced the use of EDI fulfillment and compliance to grow sales and sell into mass market and big-box chains.
- Communicated with our inside and outside sales representatives weekly to ensure efficient and profitable business.
- Compiled, analyzed, and presented key account summaries to senior management as well as other departments within the company.

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

University of Utah

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration

Towson University - Towson, MD

UMBC

Major Focus: Premedical Research Technology

INTERESTS

Web Development, UX/UI design, Mountain Biking, Rock Climbing, Snowboarding, Digital Photography